ALYSSA NATIVIDAD

Parramatta, 2150 | Phone: 0426 534 626 | Email: <u>alyssatnatividad@gmail.com</u> | Portfolio: <u>alainatividad.github.io/Portfolio-Alyssa-Natividad</u> | Github: <u>github.com/alainatividad</u> | LinkedIn: /alyssa-natividad

Profile

A talented and motivated web developer with more than five years of support experience and skilled in back-end and front-end development. Passionate with solving algorithmically complex problems to come up with sound technical solutions for everyday scenarios, as well as upskilling to grow and continue to master my craft. Recently completed a full stack development course offered by the University of Sydney, which equipped me with skills in HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design.

Projects

Weather Dashboard | alainatividad.github.io/API-Weather_Dashboard | github.com/alainatividad/API-Weather Dashboard

- Summary: Shows the current weather conditions and five-day forecast of the city entered in the search box. Weather details such as temperature, wind speed, humidity, and UV Index are shown.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Moment.js, OpenWeather API's

Workday Scheduler | alainatividad.github.io/Bootstrap-WorkDay-Scheduler | github.com/alainatividad/Bootstrap-WorkDay-Scheduler

- Summary: This application is a take on a simple day planner that allows a user to save events for each
 work hour of the day.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Moment.js

Experience

SOFTWARE SUPPORT CONSULTANT AND DEVELOPER | TALMAN PTY LTD, AUSTRALIA | JULY 2018 - PRESENT

- Provided basic IT and software support
- Assisted in the resolution of front-end and back-end support issues by investigating of Visual FoxPro (VFP) Programs
- Created Software Requirements Specifications for modifications and changes of the programs
- Developed and modified VFP Programs based on the Software Requirements Specifications
- Formulated reports using VFP based on the Software Requirements Specifications
- Created scripts to extract specific records for internal processing
- Translated existing VFP Programs to Visual DataFlex language and VFP reports to Crystal Reports format

DATASTAGE DEVELOPER | ACCENTURE INC, PHILIPPINES | JUNE 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

- Analysed and reviewed business requirements before development approval
- Prepared assessment and estimation of development work projects

- Designed and developed Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) codes and SQL components based on mapping designs and business requirements
- Conducted Quality Assurance and unit testing on the ETL and SQL codes and components by creating unit test scenarios and conditions
- Created technical documentation for ETL components

APPLICATION SUPPORT ANALYST | IBM SOLUTIONS DELIVERY INC, PHILIPPINES | AUG 2013 – MAY 2015

- Provided Level 1 application support for the Enterprise Data Warehouse of the client that processes in-store and online transactions, HR and payroll, and other business processes
- Handled low to high severity incident tickets received in line with service level agreement.
- Ensured that tickets are updated and clients are informed promptly
- Monitored batch processes and Data Warehouse jobs running using UC4 Job Scheduler
- Assisted in the resolution of front-end and back-end production support issues

Technical Skills

Database Platforms: Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, IBM DB2, Teradata

Programming Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, Express, React, Node, jQuery, Bootstrap, Shell Scripting, Visual Fox Pro, Assembly, C, Visual Dataflex, Crystal

Reports

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux/UNIX

ETL Tools: IBM Infosphere Datastage versions 8.1, 8.5 and 9.1

Software Development Tools: Git

Excellent problem-solving skills

Strong written, verbal, and listening skills developed through constant communication with clients, team members, important stakeholders, and system owners

Customer Service over the phone, through email, and through social communication tools such as IBM Sametime, Lotus Notes, and Microsoft Teams

Interpersonal and relationship building skills through experience in working with a team and offshore counterparts

Education

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT CODING BOOTCAMP | 2022 | UNIVERSITY OF SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA

INTRODUCTION TO BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE (SHORT COURSE) | 2015 | UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES – DILIMAN, NATIONAL ENGINEERING CENTER

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING | 2013 | UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES - DILIMAN

Having graduated on April 28, 2013, my coursework as a computer engineering major included programming fundamentals and applications, computer systems engineering, basic and advanced computer organization, communication systems, and computer networks & security.